Finding Aid for College of Engineering, Class of 1947 (University of Michigan) records, 1952-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
College of Engineering, Class of 1947 (University of Michigan) records 1952-2007
University of Michigan. College of Engineering. Class of 1947.
0.4 linear feet
2009093 Bimu 2
Files relating to class reunions of the University of Michigan College of Engineering class of 1947, dating from 1952 to 2007. Records include plans for a major gift to the university at the 50th reunion (a reflecting pool) and biographical information on class members.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection (Donor No. 8736 ) was received in one accession on 1/09/08 from Edward E. Moon, member of the class. 8736
No further additions to the records are expected.
The records are are open without restriction.
The class of 1947 of the University of Michigan College of Engineering included students who entered the university over a broad range of years, since most had left school during World War II to serve in the military. Although many students were considered class of 1947 by the university based on the year they completed their degrees, many 1947 graduates affiliated themselves with the class they enrolled with prior to leaving for military service.
The records from 1947 to 1987 were created by class president Harold L. Walters. After his death, class management responsibilities were taken on by Edward E. Moon.
The material in the University of Michigan College of Engineering Class of 1947 records relate mainly to class reunions, held every five years from 1952 through 2007, including materials related to fundraising for and planning of the 50th reunion gift, a reflecting pool and fountain on the university's North Campus.
The material also includes responses to questionnaires sent out around each reunion collecting information about class members since graduation relating to their occupations and personal lives. A complete roster of the class as of 1987 was compiled for the 40th reunion and can be found in that folder.
Subjects:
Engineers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; North Campus (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan. Class of 1947.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering. Class of 1947.
- Records
  - 5th Reunion: Reunion report and photo, 1947-1952 (Box 1)
  - 10th Reunion: Reunion report, including class survey, 1952-1957 (Box 1)
  - 15th & 20th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses for 15th reunion, 1957-1967 (Box 1)
  - 25th & 30th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses for 25th reunion, 1967-1977 (Box 1)
  - 35th & 40th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses and roster for 40th reunion, 1977-1987 (Box 1)
  - 45th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses, 1987-1992 (Box 1)
  - 50th Reunion/Class Gift: Correspondence and plans related to 50th-reunion class gift (reflecting pool and fountain to be built on UM North Campus), 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - 50th Reunion/Class Gift: Correspondence and plans related to 50th-reunion class gift, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - 55th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses, 1997-2002 (Box 1)
  - 60th Reunion: Reunion planning materials and class survey responses, 2002-2007 (Box 1)
Related Material
Directories (1997, 2002, 2007) and newsletters (1972) for the Engineering Class of 1947 are housed separately in University of Michigan College of Engineering publications record group under subunit publications.